Guide to the William Faulkner Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
William Faulkner collection
1944-1966
YCAL MSS 491
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
0.66
(2 boxes)
The collection consists chiefly of writings, with a small amount of correspondence. Writings include drafts of works by Faulkner and writings of others. The correspondence consists of original letters between William Faulkner and the American writer Malcolm Cowley. Also included are papers concerning the Theatre Guild and Richard Meyers production of William Faulkner's play Requiem for a Nun.
Faulkner, William, 1897-1962
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Acquired from various sources. Provenance is listed at folder level when known.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Existence and Location of Copies
Microfilm service copies are available for: Correspondence between Faulkner and Malcolm Cowley (film number 682).
William Faulkner (1897-1962)
William Faulkner, American writer. He wrote novels, short stories, a play, poetry, essays, and screenplays.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists chiefly of writings, with a small amount of correspondence. Writings include drafts of works by Faulkner and writings of others. The correspondence consists of original letters between William Faulkner and the American writer Malcolm Cowley. Also included are papers concerning the Theatre Guild and Richard Meyers theater production of William Faulkner's play Requiem for a Nun.
Arrangement
Organized into three series: I. Writings, 1949-1955. II. Correspondence, 1944-1948. III. Other Papers, 1958-1966.
American literature -- 20th Century; Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Authors -- United States -- 20th Century; Cowley, Malcolm, 1898-1989; Faulkner, William, 1897-1962; Meyers, Richard; Theatre Guild
- Writings, 1949-1955, undated; Series I; 0.66; (2 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically.
  - "Don Manuel" and "Orpheus," typescript drafts and photocopies of poems, undated (Box 1)
    Custodial History
    Gift of Phil Stone, 1947
  - "Gold is Not Always," typescript draft and corrected galley proofs for publication in Atlantic Monthly, undated (Box 1)
    Gift of R. E. Danielson, 1941
  - "One Day," autobiographical note, handwritten and carbon typescript corrected drafts, undated; 2 (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Typescripts are were transcribed by E. Izsak, 1968 June 6. Includes note by Izsak
  - "The Reivers," typescript photocopied proofs, undated; 2 (Box 1)
    Gift of the Book of the Month Club, year unknown
  - "That Evening Sun," handwritten draft and photostats, typescript transcript and photocopies, undated; 3 (Box 1)
    Includes note from Saxe Commins of Random House to Norman Holmes Pearson, 1955 January 24
  - "To the Youth of Japan," speech, typescript, undated (Box 1)
    Includes note: "This speech was recorded by a State Department official who accompanied Faulkner on his trip through Japan."
    Gift of George Soule, year unknown
  - National Book Award address, press release, 1955 January 25 (Box 1)
  - Nobel Prize in Literature award speech, typescript carbon draft. Signed and presented by Dudley Nichols, 1949 (Box 1)
    Gift of Dudley Nichols, 1953
- Correspondence, 1944-1948, undated; Series II
  - Correspondence between Faulkner and Malcolm Cowley, 1944-1948, undated; 2 (Box 1)
    Accompanied by list of letters and dates with letter from Cowley to Norman Holmes Pearson, 1947 November 27
    Gift of Malcolm Cowley, 1949 and 1962
- Other Papers, 1958-1966, undated; Series III
  - The Faulkner-Cowley File: Letters and Memories, 1944-1962 by Malcolm Cowley. Galley proofs, corrected, 1966 (Box 1)
    Gift of Malcolm Cowley, 1967
  - "Metropolitan Broadcasting Television presents 'William Faulkner's Mississippi.' Narrated by Montgomery Clift and Zachary Scott. Produced by Robert Guenette, directed by Don Horan." Typescript script, undated (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, contracts, and other papers concerning the Theatre Guild and Richard Meyers theater production of William Faulkner's Requiem for a Nun, 1958-1959; 26 (Box 2)
    Accompanied by folder listing